Guide to the School of Medicine, Yale University, Records of Standing and Ad Hoc Committees
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
School of Medicine, Yale University, records of standing and ad hoc committees
1956-1986
RU 229
Yale University. Department of Manuscripts and Archives
4.25
The records consist of correspondence, job descriptions, minutes, notes and related materials documenting the Development Advisory Committee, deanship search committees, and other committees of the Yale School of Medicine.
Yale University. School of Medicine
General note
Forms part of Yale Record Group 27-D (YRG 27-D), Records of committees of the Yale School of Medicine.
Conditions Governing Access
Access to the records is restricted. See Collection Contents for details.
Scope and Contents
The records consist of correspondence, job descriptions, minutes, notes and related materials documenting the Development Advisory Committee, deanship search committees, and other committees of the Yale School of Medicine.
Arrangement
The records are arranged by accession.
Universities and colleges -- Administration; Yale University -- Administration; Yale University. School of Medicine
- Records of the Committee for the Selection of a Dean, 1956; Accession 1966-A-001
  Conditions Governing Access
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2032.
  - Correspondence, lists, minutes regarding selection of a dean. Kept by Byron H. Wakernan, 1956 (Box 1)
- Records of the Deanship Search Committee, 1970-1971; Accession 1987-A-050
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2047.
  - Search committee members (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Correspondence (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Job descriptions, drafts and copies (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Suggested candidates for the Clinical Deanship (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Comments on new deanships by Astrahan, Redlich & Lippard (Box 1, Folder 5)
- Committee records, 1981-1984; Accession 1991-A-078
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2020.
  - Develpment advisory committee, 1981-1984 (Box 1, Folder 1-5)
  - Yale Medical School committees, 1982-1984 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Memorandum and report re: The Willard Burr Soper Fund for The Advancement of Medicine, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 7)
- Records of the Clinical Investigation, Human Investigation and Do Not Resuscitate committees, 1960-1986; Accession 1995-A-053 (Box 1–6)
  Restricted until Jan 1, 2022.
  Scope and Contents
  No inventory available.